Guide to the Julian Sorell Huxley Papers, 1899-1980 MS 050
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series V: Manuscripts, Typescripts, and Notes, 256850
  - Bird Notes, 1946-1948; 257081 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - 1948, 257080 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - A Bird in the Bois, 1948; 257079 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Toy Wheels, 1948; 257078 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - List of Articles and Photos, 1948-1949; 257077 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Experimental Biology, 1949; 257076 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Tyrian Murex - Communal Display in the Shield-Duck, 1949; 257075 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Evolution Lecture, No. 2, 1949; 257074 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Notes, 1949; 257073 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - An Arts Council for Africa?, 1949; 257072 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Bird-Watching Notes, 1949; 257071 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - 1949, 257070 (Box 67, Folder 7-8)
  - Song-Variants in the Wood Pigeon, 1949; 257069 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Undateable, 1940s; 257068 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - The British Contribution to Knowledge of the Living Bird, 1940s; 257067 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - On Helping History, 1940s; 257066 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - A Rare Planet and its Background, 1940s; 257065 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Notes, 1940s; 257064 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Allometric Growth, 1940s; 257063 (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Notes, 1940s; 257062 (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Unfinished manuscript: "100 Years Hence", 1940s; 257061 (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - 1950, 257060 (Box 68, Folder 1-3)
  - "Genetical Jubilee", 1950; 257059 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - 1950, 257058 (Box 68, Folder 5-6)
  - "New Naturalist" Autobiography, 1950-1951; 257057 (Box 68, Folder 7-9)
  - Birds and Science, 1950; 257056 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - The Integration of Human Destiny, 1950?; 257055 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Undated, 1950s, 257054 (Box 68, Folder 12-14)
  - Unesco History, 1950; 257053 (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - 1951, 257052 (Box 69, Folder 1-3)
  - Eo hippus, 1951; 257051 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Lecture Notes - BBC series "Humanity and Evolution", 1951; 257050 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Patten Lecutre II, May 2, 1951; 257049 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Evolution in Action (published NY, Harper, 1951? 1953); 257048 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - The Greatest English Naturalist - Darwin, April 28, 1951; 257047 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Preamble, 1952; 257046 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - 1952, 257045 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - 1952, 257044 (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Notes, 1952?; 257043 (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - 1952, 257042 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - 1952, 257041 (Box 69, Folder 14)
  - Evolutionary Humanism, 1952; 257040 (Box 69, Folder 15)
  - Ancient and Modern, 1952-1953; 257039 (Box 69, Folder 16)
  - 1953, 257038 (Box 69, Folder 17-21)
  - Kalinga Prize Speech, 1953; 257037 (Box 69, Folder 22)
  - Notes, etc. "Evolution in Action", 1953; 257036 (Box 69, Folder 23)
  - 1954, 257035 (Box 70, Folder 1-5)
  - Notes "1954 on", 257034 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Notes - Not Needed, 1954; 257033 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Psychology in Evolutionary Perspective, 1954; 257032 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Scientific Humanism, Evolution, and Human Destiny, 1954; 257031 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - 1955, 257030 (Box 70, Folder 10-12)
  - Idea Systems Group - Notes & Lecture Outlines, "Evolutionary Humanism", 1955; 257029 (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - Areesha, 1955; 257028 (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - Toynbee and Time-Scales, 1954; 257027 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - The Evolution of Man - incl. Hawkes, Pumphrey Tss., 1955; 257026 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Animals, Suschitzky, 1955; 257025 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Notes for Love Article, 1955; 257024 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Heterosis and Morphism, 1955; 257023 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Notes, 1950s; 257022 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Portugal, 1950s; 257021 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Nuzhdin Statement, 1950s; 257020 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Maia, 1950s; 257019 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Notes, etc. -, Undated; 257018 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Lecture Notes -, Undated 1950s(?); 257017 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - From an Antique Land, 1954; 257016 (Box 72, Folder 1-19)
  - Notes, 1956; 257015 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Sloan Kettering, 1956; 257014 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - 1956, 257013 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Secrets of Life, 1956; 257012 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - 1956, 257011 (Box 73, Folder 5-9)
  - 1957, 257010 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - Biographical Notes on darwin, 1957; 257009 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Uppsala - diagrams, 1957; 257008 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - 1957, 257007 (Box 73, Folder 13-15)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Lecture, 1957; 257006 (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - Evolution of Mind, 1957 (?); 257005 (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - Review: P. Medawar, The Uniqueness of the Individual, 1957; 257004 (Box 73, Folder 18)
  - Excuse me, but your Id is showing, 1958; 257003 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Foreword, Cyril Bibby -, 1958; 257002 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Review: Tinbergen, Curious Naturalists, 1958; 257001 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Rene Bere, the Two Lords of Africa, 1958; 257000 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - 1958, 256999 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Pugwash - Humanist Manifesto, 1958; 256998 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - McGill Lecture, 1958; 256997 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Teilhard de Chardin, 1958; 256996 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - 1958, 256995 (Box 74, Folder 9-11)
  - Guy the Gorilla, 1958; 256994 (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - "The Synthesis", 1958; 256993 (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - "Adventures of the Mind", 1958-1959; 256992 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - "Evolution - Introduction", 1958-1959; 256991 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Notes - "The Humanist Frame", 1959; 256990 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - "The Humanist Frame" materials, 1959; 256989 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - "The Impending Crisis", 1959; 256988 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - 1959, 256987 (Box 75, Folder 6-7)
  - Evolution - Population, 1959; 256986 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Lasker Award Address, 1959; 256985 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Argonne National Laboratory Address, 1959; 256984 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Notes, 1050s; 256983 (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - "C.D.'s Achievements", 1950s; 256982 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Evolution MSS, duplicates", 1950s; 256981 (Box 75, Folder 13)
  - "A Goosely Fixation", 1950s(?); 256980 (Box 75, Folder 14)
  - "Humanist Frame" (including copies of correspondence), 1959-1960; 256979 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Humanist Frame, 1960; 256978 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - The Humanist Frame, 256977 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - The Humanist Frame, 1960-1961; 256976 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - 1960, 256975 (Box 76, Folder 5-11)
  - Unesco Report, 1960; 256974 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Unesco "History of Mankind", 1961; 256973 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - "Humanist Frame and Evolution and Theology", 1961; 256972 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - The Humanist Frame, 1961; 256971 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - "Humanist Frame Introduction", 1961; 256970 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Roger Godel, 1961; 256969 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Review: J.M. Tanner, "Education and Physical Growth", 1961; 256968 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - "Ngorongoro", 1961; 256967 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - General Knowledge Encyclopedia "Keyboard", 1961; 256966 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - "Article for Endeavor", 1961; 256965 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - "Serengeti", 1961; 256964 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - "Human Ecology - Population and Conservation", 1961; 256963 (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - 1961, 256962 (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - 1961, 256961 (Box 77, Folder 13)
  - 1961, 256960 (Box 78, Folder 1-5)
  - "I Remember", 1961; 256959 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - "McGill, St. Louis, San Francisco" (lecture notes), 1961; 256958 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - "Ghana Lecture Notes", 1961; 256957 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - "Evolution", 1961; 256956 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - "Evolutionary Humanism", 1961; 256955 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - 1962, 256954 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - "Galton Lecture" - see folder 79.4, 1962; 256953 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - "Psychometabolism", 1962; 256952 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - "Eugenics in Evolutionary Perspective", 1962; 256951 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - "New Vision Library", 1962; 256950 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - (Proposed) Ecological Survey of Masailand, 1962; 256949 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - "Evolution", 1962; 256948 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - "Africa", 1962; 256947 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - John Danz Lecture, 1962; 256946 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - 1962, 256945 (Box 80, Folder 1-5)
  - Review: Dobzhansky's "Mankind Evolving", 1962; 256944 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - "Psychometabolism notes and MS", 1962; 256943 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - "Education and the Humanist Revolution" Fawley Foundation Lecture, 1962; 256942 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - "Education and the Humanist Revolution", 256941 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - "Population, Humanist Revolution Lecture Notes", 1962; 256940 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - "CIBA MS", 1962; 256939 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - "Jordan: Land of Desert History", 1963; 256938 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - "Jordan", 1963; 256937 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - "Jordan Article", 1963; 256936 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - "Jordan", 1963; 256935 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - International Union forConservation of Nature Program, 1963; 256934 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - "Race Hatred", 1963; 256933 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - 1963, 256932 (Box 81, Folder 7-11)
  - Danz Lecture, 1963; 256931 (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - Danz Lecture, 1963; 256930 (Box 81, Folder 13)
  - "Lorenzian Ethnology", 1963; 256929 (Box 81, Folder 14)
  - African anturalist Series, 1963; 256928 (Box 81, Folder 15)
  - Aldous Huxley's Memorial Service, 1963; 256927 (Box 81, Folder 16)
  - Konrad Lorenz Festshrift Notes, 1963; 256926 (Box 81, Folder 17)
  - "Psychometabolism", 1963; 256925 (Box 81, Folder 18)
  - 1963, 256924 (Box 82, Folder 1-2)
  - "Evolution Introduction", 1963; 256923 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - 1964, 256922 (Box 82, Folder 4-11)
  - "Old Schizo Msc", 1964; 256921 (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - "Evolution, New Edition", 1964; 256920 (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - "Charles Darwin: Galapagos and After", 1964; 256919 (Box 82, Folder 14)
  - "Charles Darwin: Galapagos and After", 1964; 256918 (Box 82, Folder 15)
  - "Psychometabolism", 1964; 256917 (Box 82, Folder 16)
  - "Nature's Network", 1964; 256916 (Box 82, Folder 17)
  - "Growth of Ideas", 1964; 256915 (Box 82, Folder 18)
  - "Schizophrenia as a Genetic Morphism", 1964; 256914 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Essays of a Humanist, 1964; 256913 (Box 83, Folder 2-4)
  - "Unpublished MSS on Africa", 1960s; 256912 (Box 83, Folder 5-7)
  - "Fitness", 1965; 256911 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - "Fitness and Evolution", 1965; 256910 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Ritualization Symposium, 1965; 256909 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Unesco History, 1965; 256908 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - "ART", 1965; 256907 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - "Darwin and His World", 1965; 256906 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - 1965, 256905 (Box 84, Folder 7-13)
  - 1965-1966, 256904 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - 1966, 256903 (Box 85, Folder 2-4)
  - "Wildlife Africa", 1966; 256902 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - 1967, 256901 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Review: "Mumford's Myth of the Machine", 1967; 256900 (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - 1968, 256899 (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - 1969, 256898 (Box 85, Folder 9-11)
  - Notes on Conversation with Joy Adamson, 1969; 256897 (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - "Modern Crisis in Religion", 1960s; 256896 (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - 1960s, 256895 (Box 85, Folder 14)
  - "Development of the Biological Sciences", 1960s(?); 256894 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - "Population", 1950s, 1960s; 256893 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - "Population", 1960s; 256892 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - "Science and Synthesis", 1960s; 256891 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - 1960s Autobiographical Notes, 256890 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Undated 1960s, 256889 (Box 86, Folder 6-13)
  - Odette Keun notes -, 1970; 256888 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - 1970, 256887 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - "Eugenics in Evolutionary Perspective", 1970; 256886 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Notes, 1971; 256885 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - 1971, 256884 (Box 87, Folder 5-6)
  - "Huxley Commemoration", 1972; 256883 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Imperial College Lecture, 1972; 256882 (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Notes, 1972; 256881 (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Notes, 1972; 256880 (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - 1972, 256879 (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - Zoological Society Medal Lecture, 1973; 256878 (Box 87, Folder 12)
  - 1973, 256877 (Box 87, Folder 13)
  - 1974, 256876 (Box 87, Folder 14)
  - Undated 1970s, 256875 (Box 87, Folder 15)
  - Notes, 1970s; 256874 (Box 87, Folder 16)
  - Notes from books in JSH Library, 256873 (Box 87, Folder 17)
  - Notes removed from JSH Library, 256872 (Box 87, Folder 18)
  - Growth of Ideas, 256871 (Box 88, Folder 1-6)
  - Autobiography, 256870 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Memories 1, 256869 (Box 89, Folder 2-5)
  - Drawing - Crested Grebe - "Memories", 256868 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - "Memories" - Notebook I, 256867 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - "Memories 1" - Notebook II, 256866 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - "Memories 1" - Notebook III, 256865 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - "Memories 1" - Notebook IV, 256864 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - "Memories 1" - Notebook V, 256863 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - "Memories 2" - Notebook VI, 256862 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - "Memories 2" - >Notebook VII, 256861 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Memories 1" - JSH/ THH correspondence photo copy, 256860 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - "Memories 1" - Typescript, 256859 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Preface, "Memories 2", 256858 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - "Memories 2" Permission to Quote, 256857 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Memories 2, 256856 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Memories 2, 256855 (Box 93, Folder 1-3)
  - "Memories 1" Uncorrected Copy, 256854 (Box 93, Folder 4-5)
  - Memories 1, 256853 (Box 94, Folder 1-2)
  - Memories 2, 256852 (Box 95, Folder 1-6)
  - JSH Manuscripts, Notes. Memories 2, 256851 (Box 96, Folder 1-2)
- Series VI: Publications by Julian Huxley, 1920-1974, 256792
  The publications series contains material (exclusive of books) published by Sir Julian: reprints of scholarly works, newspaper and magazine articles, as well as letters to editors and reviews of the works of others. This series covers the time period from 1920 to 1974, and is arranged in chronological order. A list of these materials is in the first folder of the first box in the series.
  The series does not comprise the whole of Sir Julian's printed work. It consists, rather, of those reprints and clippings which he retained in his files. Those interested in a complete bibliography of Sir Julian's work should consult John Baker's Julian Huxley, Scientist and World Citizen, (Paris: Unesco, 1978).
  - Bibliography of JSH Publications, 256849 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - 1920, 256848 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - 1921, 256847 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - 1922-23, 256846 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - 1924-25, 256845 (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Rice Institute Pamphlet "The Outlook in Biology", 1924; 256844 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - 1926, 256843 (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - 1927, 256842 (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - 1928-29, 256841 (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - 1920s, 256840 (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - 1930, 256839 (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - 1931, 256838 (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - 1931-32, 256837 (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - 1933, 256836 (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - The Listener, 1933; 256835 (Box 97, Folder 14)
  - 1934, 256834 (Box 97, Folder 15)
  - 1935, 256833 (Box 97, Folder 16)
  - Yale Review, (duplicate), Summer 1935; 256832 (Box 97, Folder 17)
  - 1936, 256831 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - 1937, 256830 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - 1938, 256829 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - 1939, 256828 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - 1938-39, 256827 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - 1940, 256826 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Articles, 1941; 256825 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - 1942, 256824 (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Articles, 1942; 256823 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - 1943, 256822 (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - 1944, 256821 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Articles, 1945; 256820 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - articles, 1946-47; 256819 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - 1948, 256818 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - 1949, 256817 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - 1950, 256816 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - 1951, 256815 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - 1952, 256814 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - 1953, 256813 (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - 1953-54, 256812 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - 1955, 256811 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - 1956, 256810 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - 1957, 256809 (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - 1958, 256808 (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - 1959, 256807 (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - 1960, 256806 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - 1961, 256805 (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - 1962, 256804 (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - 1963, 256803 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - 1964, 256802 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - 1965, 256801 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - 1966, 256800 (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - 1967, 256799 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - 1968, 256798 (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - 1969, 256797 (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - 1960s (undated), 256796 (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - 1971, 256795 (Box 101, Folder 12)
  - 1974, 256794 (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - Bibliographic Note Cards, 256793 (Box 101, Folder 14)
- Series VII: Travel Materials, 1912-1965, 256757
  This series comprises a mixture of travel diaries, notes, collected documents and memorabilia such as programs and exhibit catalogues filed chronologically by the year of each trip. Newspaper articles included here provide more information than the often sketchy notes, telling of Huxley's debate on Soviet science with Nuzhdin in Karachi, 1954, or his attendance at a meeting concerned with nuclear weapons in New York in 1961. Unesco is well represented here, with diaries of the 1946-47 trips to South and Central America and the 1948-49 trip to Central Europe and the Middle East. Note that conference materials and photographs have been separated to their respective categories, including the 1959 U.S. trip for the Darwin Centenary, the Wroclaw conference, 1948, and the Indian Science Conference, 1954. Note also that some of the publications collected as part of Huxley's travel assignments - reports on conservation for example - are filed with MANUSCRIPTS, PUBLICATIONS AND ADDRESSES BY OTHERS. Materials on Huxley's Russian trip may also be found in the BOX FILES.
  - Heidelberg, 1913; 256791 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - USA, 1912, 1914-15; 256790 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Italy, 1918; 256789 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Spitzbergen, 1921; 256788 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Africa, 1929; 256787 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - USA, Canada, 1930-32; 256786 (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Canada and USA, St. Kilda, USA, USA and Lisbon, 1935; 1939; 1939-40; 1941-42; 256785 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Journals, West Africa, 1944; 256784 (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - West Africa, 1944; 256783 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - USA, USSR, 1945; [1945?], 1945; 256782 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Latin America, 1946; 256781 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Latin America, 1947; 256780 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Unesco tour, Middle East, April-May 1948; 256779 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Unesco tour, Eastern Europe, Summer 1948; 256778 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Amsterdam and Les Eyzies, August 1948; 256777 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Unesco tour, Middle East, November 1948-1949; 256776 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Iceland, Sweden, USA, Italy, Summer 1949; 1950; 1950, 1951; 1953; 256775 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - World Tour Itinerary, USA and Fiji Islands, 1953-54; 1953; 256774 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - World Tour, Australia, 1953; 256773 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - World Tour, Australia, 1953; 256772 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - World Tour, Near East Itineraries, 1953-54; 256771 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - World Tour, Near East Journals, 1953-54; 256770 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - World Tour, Near East Journals, 1953-54; 256769 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - World Tour, Near East Clippings, Notes, Collected documents, 1953-54; 256768 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - World Tour, Near East collected documents and memorabilia, 1953-54; 256767 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Canada and USA, Canada India, USA, 1954; 1956; 1959; 1959; 256766 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - South Africa and East Africa, 1960; 256765 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - South Africa and Eastern Africa, Journals, 1960; 256764 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - West Africa, 1961; 256763 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - West Africa, 1961; 256762 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - West Africa, 1961; 256761 (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - USA and Canada USA Oslo, 1961; 1962; 1962; 256760 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - British Jordan Expedition, Afrida, USA, 1963; 1963; 1964; 256759 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Africa, 1965; 256758 (Box 105, Folder 9)
- Series VIII: Conference Materials, 1934-1965, 256690
  This series contains papers relating to conferences, meetings and symposia in which Huxley took part. These papers include programs, newspaper clippings, abstracts and papers of participants, and Huxley's notes and speech manuscripts. Correspondence concerning the conferences included in this series is to be found among the Huxley correspondence files. In some cases, however, copies of original letters have been included with the relevant conference or symposium papers.
  Materials from conferences which Huxley did not attend are filed in the MANUSCRIPTS, PUBLICATIONS AND ADDRESSES BY OTHERS series.
  Of particular interest among the conference materials are papers dealing with the Wroclaw (Breslau) Conference, the Darwin Centennial Observation and the Royal Society Symposium on Ritualization of Behavior in Animals and Man.
  - Public Health Congress and Exhibition Voluntary Sterilisation, 1934; 256756 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Anniversary Russian Academy of Science, 1945; 256755 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Sixth Conference on Science, Philosophy, and Religion, [1940s?]; 256754 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - World Congress of Intellectuals Cultural World Congress for Peace (Wroclaw-Breslau), 1948; 256753 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Wroclaw Conference (Breslau), 1948; 256752 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Wroclaw (Breslau), 1948; 256751 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Wroclaw (Breslau), 1949; 256750 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Wroclaw (Breslau), 1948; 256749 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - International Council of Museums, 1949; 256748 (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - 10th International Ornithological Congress, 1950; 256747 (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - Society for Visiting Scientists, 1950; 256746 (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - "The Frontier of Knowledge", Sept. 1951-May 1952; 256745 (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Twelfth Conference on Science, Philosophy, and Religion, 1952; 256744 (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - Thirteenth Conference on Science, Philosophy, and Religion, 1952; 256743 (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - Race Problems in the Light of Modern Science, 1952; 256742 (Box 106, Folder 15)
  - First International Congress on Humanism and Ethical Culture, 1952; 256741 (Box 106, Folder 16)
  - First International Congress on Humanism and Ethical Culture papers given, 1952; 256740 (Box 106, Folder 17)
  - First International Congress on Humanism and Ethical Culture, 1952; 256739 (Box 106, Folder 18)
  - Symposium on Ecology of Coral Atolls, 1953; 256738 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Unesco Humanism and Education in East and West, 1953; 256737 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Social Policy and the Social Sciences Conference 1953 Program, 256736 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Sixth Pakistan Science Conference, 1954; 256735 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - World Conference of Scientists, 1955; 256734 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Pugwash, 1955-57; 256733 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Sixth International Conference on Planned Parenthood, New Delhi, 1959; 256732 (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - Planned Parenthood, 1959; 256731 (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - Markle Scholar Meeting, 1959; 256730 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - "The Future of Man" Symposium, 1959; 256729 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - Science Association of Nigeria Fourth Annual Conference, 1961; 256728 (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - The Second Corning Conference, 1961; 256727 (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - Tenth Pugwash Conference on Science and World Affairs, 1962; 256726 (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - Tenth Pugwash Conference, 1962; 256725 (Box 107, Folder 14)
  - Pugwash (history), 256724 (Box 107, Folder 15)
  - IUCN Conference, 1963; 256723 (Box 107, Folder 16)
  - Seventh International Conference on Planned Parenthood, 1963; 256722 (Box 107, Folder 17)
  - The Galapagos Islands Symposium, 1964; 256721 (Box 107, Folder 18)
  - Zoological Society of London/ WHO Symposium, 1965; 256720 (Box 107, Folder 19)
  - G. Mendel Symposium, Symposium on the Mutational Process, 1965; 256719 (Box 107, Folder 20)
  - International Congress of the World Wildlife Fund, 1970; 256718 (Box 107, Folder 21)